Endia Williams

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Portfolio

endia.dev Agithub.com/endiawilliams 🖸

Contact

contact@endia.dev linkedin.com/in/endia-dev in 631-948-4568 Kansas City, MO 64133 ♀

Summary

I'm a full-stack engineer with a passion for responsive design & dynamic code. Having both a creative & a scientific turn of mind, I enjoy every part of the development process from start to finish. My diverse background gives me experience cooperating & communicating with a wide variety of people & allows me to see many perspectives. I take pride in what I do & always deliver the most efficient & elegant code possible.

Skills

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- JavaScript, React, Node, Express
- Python
- PostgreSQL
- Docker
- Git & GitHub

Projects

Minesweeper

 Created a Minesweeper clone utilizing mutual recursion with vanilla JavaScript in 1 week.

When in Roam

 Developed a full-stack app with full CRUD functionality and authentication using Node in 1 week.

BetterCupid DevOps

- Created a full-stack React app with full CRUD functionality and authentication with 2 team mates in 2 weeks.
- Implemented CI/CD and deployed backend to Google Cloud.

Experience

Client Coordinator

FrontStreet Facility Solutions, Ronkonkoma, NY (2018-2019)

- Assisted retail clients in securing plumbers & handymen for timely & cost-effective repair service.
- Provided detailed and accurate quotes up to \$5,000 for plumbing & facilities repairs to clients.

Shift Lead

Speedway Convenience Store, Wading River, NY (2017-2018)

- Processed transactions, maintained store cleanliness & assisted customers as needed.
- Accepted additional responsibilities such as keeping track of inventory and supervising up to 3 additional employees when management was absent.

Data Entry Clerk

The American Legion, Indianapolis, IN (2014-2016)

• Entered data for 1000s of paper-based member records into a custom database, ensuring that information was entered with few to no errors & submitted in a timely manner.

Education

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly (2020)

Liberal Arts

Ivy Tech Community College, Indianapolis, IN (2013-2014)